Farewell, Earth
The ship that is departing is
The Space Battleship
Yamato
It departs now to Iscandar,
at the end of the cosmos,
bearing its fate.
"We will come back, no matter what it takes"
Answer with a smile to the waving people
Going far from the Galaxy towards Iscandar
A faint gleam of hope
The Space Battleship Yamato
Welcome back.
Thank you.
Welcome back
Planet Iscandar... An Earth-type planet whose surface is eighty percent water.
We made it.
Yeah.
Crew of the Yamato. This is Okita, your captain.
We have finally reached Iscandar.
Look... Iscandar lies before you.
As your captain, I have just one thing I'd like to say to you.
Thank you... That is all.
Iscandar will now guide the Yamato to the planet's surface.
Surface temperature is 27 degrees. Air pressure is 1,023 hectopascals.
On the Beaufort scale, the wind is 2, to south. The sea is calm, and the sky is clear.
We will return Yurisha. Kodai and Niimi, come with me.
Yes, sir.
You, too, Mori.
The city is very quiet.
She will be here soon.
Welcome home, Yurisha.
And you, as well, Sasha.
No, this is...
Mori Yuki...
She is an Earthling.
Uh...
It seems she thought Mori was Sasha.
She lost her life on Mars, bringing us the Wave Motion Core.
Sasha...
The Earth owes her its survival.
I see...
And yet, you used the Wave Motion Energy as a weapon.
But that was—
Kodai!
What is your name?
Susumu Kodai.
I am Executive Officer Shiro Sanada,
here on the Captain's behalf. She is...
Information Officer Kaoru Niimi.
Yurisha, tell me what you have seen.
I shall speak with the people from Earth afterward.
Yes.
You're kidding me...
What do you mean?
Yeah, she said we can't have the Cosmo Reverse System.
Does that mean she wants everyone on Earth to die?!
From what I heard, she simply wants some time.
Either way, it's an insult!
Will she really give it to us?
We just need to believe.
Everyone's uneasy...
Of course they are... Everyone was happy we'd finally made it.
Keep your feet on the ground.
...Is what the Captain would say.
We need to do something.
Um, Medic Harada has a suggestion!
Hoshina, can you swim?
I think so.
Nice idea, Makoto!
Yeah, the sea is right here! We need to let off some steam.
Exactly.
Where's Kato? Isn't he coming?
Oh, yeah!
Well...
Tokugawa got him.
Oh...
Shino!
It's your turn.
High... Too high!
Not bad.
Naturally.
Shino...
Nature's so nice...
You've got that right.
Guys are stupid.
This really is nice...
Hmm?
Ships belong on the sea.
Yeah.
I'm not good with waiting.
I see... So Lord Desler has passed away.
Yes, the Yamato saved us. We have no further issues with them.
Even if you do not, I do.
Abelt...
My dream is the great unification of Garmillas and Iscandar.
That would be impossible... Our ideals are too different.
Our task is...
Then I shall fulfill your task.
I promise you that I will grant your wish.
And I will bring peace to all the planets.
Even if I save the humans, they'll follow the same path you did.
And I would add that it was
the cannon that uses Wave Motion Energy which saved us.
We can handle the rest on our own.
Rud Iscandar.
Yurisha?
Please give the Cosmo Reverse System to the Earthlings.
I am considering it.
They are not like the Iscandarians, or the Garmillans.
The Yamato used the Wave Motion Gun in self-defense.
In order to survive.
The scent of the sea... When did I last smell that?
I'd like to take this odor back...
Yeah, that's why we're here.
The smell of salt air can be replicated artificially.
You're a boring little robot, you know? I'll teach you to drink sometime.
I cannot drink.
It has a seventy-eight percent chance of causing a system error.
You really are boring!
It's gotten cold. This is a night for hot sake.
Yes. I understand that they could not have made it so far otherwise.
And that they used the power to save their enemy.
But...
Yes, the will to survive...
They have that.
I understand that.
I must tell them about you. She was here, as well...
But if I do, I'll never see you again...
This planet is too sad...
So pretty.
What are these flowers called?
Blue Crystal.
Blue Crystal?
Will flowers like these bloom on Earth again?
In the language of flowers, they mean "hidden life" and "hidden emotion."
Hidden life?
When a planet bears life,
its matter, and its life forms' evolutionary memories,
exist as a Wave Motion, beyond time and space.
The planet's element, matter that contains its emotions, releases those memories.
Without that element here, the Cosmo Reverser cannot be completed.
The only way to save the Earth, was for you to come here.
And you came.
With the Yamato.
Matter that contains the planet's emotions?
That is...
Yes.
How long do you suppose they'll keep us waiting?
Do you think they'll even give it to us?
For now, let us have faith.
Hey, what is that?
Excuse me, but may I ask what you want?
There is no need for concern.
Starsha!
I have come to give you the Cosmo Reverser.
An element?
Yes.
And what is required for use as an element?
This ship.
In... In other words...
I shall remake this ship.
And the Yamato itself will become
the system for the Cosmo Reverser.
Understood.
I must simply pray my decision was the correct one.
We made the hand of salvation you offered us, into a weapon of destruction.
We are well aware of the gravity of this deed.
What you call the Wave Motion Gun...
We were the first to make it.
Iscandar once used its power,
to stain the Large Magellanic Cloud with blood, to forge a mighty empire.
More than any other, we know the terror of that weapon.
So we never gave the technology to anyone.
Promise me...
That you will never repeat our foolish act.
I promise.
You... Susumu Kodai, was it?
Yes...
May I have a word?
Where are we going now?
Is this a graveyard?
Iscandar's people sleep below.
Everyone, save the two of us, is here.
I imagine you realized this once you saw the town.
This planet is the only one that need suffer this sadness.
Eiji Ishizu
Mamoru Kodai
How?
Why is my brother's name here?
He was on board a Garmillan prisoner-transport ship
that crashed on Iscandar.
They were carrying him as a bio-sample of humanity.
But he was the only one to survive.
I managed to hide him from Garmillas. But his body was already...
In the end, I couldn't save anyone...
I see.
I am Captain of the Cosmo Navy Destroyer Yukikaze, Mamoru Kodai.
I was captured by Garmillans, and was being transported as an experimental sample.
When the ship crashed, I was saved by an Iscandarian woman.
And she told me that a ship from Earth was heading here.
If you're hearing this message, you must have made it.
I wish I could return to Earth with you, aboard your ship.
But it appears I will not last that long.
Before I die, there are two things I wish to say.
The first is that we can come to an understanding with the aliens.
Since I arrived, I have learned that.
I hope you will not forget it.
And second, I want you to tell my brother, Susumu...
Susumu, live for me, as well!
Live, and see the Earth when it's become blue once more!
I pray for your safe voyage.
May you return safely to Earth!
I see, Kodai passed away here.
He sleeps peacefully. Not in the coldness of space, but here, in this land...
Let us return, Sanada.
It was his wish and our task.
Yes, sir.
Is that true?
Yes, I shall go to Garmillas.
There, I shall assist the people.
Irun Yurisha
Yuki, this is a sign of the bond between us.
Hidden life... Hidden emotions.
We share a mindset.
That's my line.
The Yamato will now finish reception of the Cosmo Reverser and return to Earth.
Let us return home.
Weigh anchor!
Goodbye, Kodai...
Farewell, my other self.
Farewell, Mamoru...
Episode 24
The Distant Promised Land
This star is the only one
If you look for something so beautiful
It is not something you can see
You will find it inside anyone
Love is the answer
Sorrow and strife
May cloud the blue sky
The overlapping warmth
Becomes a light to illuminate the world
A wish to the infinite universe
All is forgiven
And we all laugh together
Not a trick of the eye
But a dream from the bottom of my heart
No matter what tomorrow brings
Walk on
If you have nothing special
Only the strength to yearn for it
Bound to the limits of time
Create the trace of a miracle
A wish to the infinite universe
All is forgiven
And we all laugh together
Not a trick of the eye
A dream from the bottom of my heart
No matter what tomorrow brings
Walk on
Together with you
Forever
With Iscandar behind it, the Yamato hurries back to Earth.
Will they make it?
They arrive at the Balun gate, hoping to speed up their return.
But there, they see that man... Their enemy. Can they see a future beyond him?
Next time: The Forever War.
There are 143 days left before humanity is extinct.